Phụ đề được chỉnh sửa từ phụ đề
trên OpenSubtitles.org
Con người đang phải
nỗ lực để vực dậy
Từ một đợt nắng nóng
kỉ lục,
và nó đang chỉ trở nên tồi tệ hơn.
Hiện giờ, nó là cơn lũ.
Toàn bộ các thị trấn đã biến
thành tro tàn.
Những đám cháy lúc này
là tồi tệ nhất...
Nạn phá rừng đang gia tăng
một cách nhanh chóng
REPORTER #4: Oxygen levels
plummet from deforestation.
REPORTER #5: Extinction revelers
lost the war today.
REPORTER #6:
...as the last tree on Earth
was logged in the Amazon.
REPORTER #7: Large areas of
ocean algae are dying.
Revolution over Europe
now so widespread...
REPORTER #8: Fatal respiratory
illness...
REPORTER #9: Is the biggest
killer in more
than 100 countries
across the globe.
REPORTER #10:
Plant life extinct,
food rations oversubscribed...
REPORTER #11: And supplies are
stretched beyond...
REPORTER #12: What the local
charities can support.
REPORTER #13: Overpopulation in
Africa and the Middle East
now catastrophic.
REPORTER #14: Reports of oxygen
content droptín hiệu.
REPORTER #15:
Synthetic oxygen supplies
buckle under demand
as the UN disbands.
REPORTER #16:
Thousands suffocate in...
REPORTER #17: And now,
Canada has gone dark.
Ta đã mất Ấn Độ.
REPORTER #19: After losing
Belgium...
Đức đã ngắt kết nối.
Trung Quốc bây giờ hoàn toàn tối đen.
REPORTER #20: In all of the
Middle East since January...
REPORTER #21: O2 supplies
dangerously low as...
REPORTER #22: As survivors flood
to the last...
...thành phố cuối cùng
không bị bóng tối bao trùm.
GRID:
Emergency reroute required.
90 seconds until
nuclear core overload.
You down the hall tonight?
Why? You going to grace us
with your presence?
JUDE: Fill up both.
See if she'll hold.
GRID: Danger.
Evacuate utility tunnel.
Yeah. She'll hold.
And hell no, I'm not going.
JUDE: Oh, come on, man.
There'll be booze
and small talk.
Not for all the oxygen
in the world.
Này.
Hanging around a bunch
of lowlife foggers.
Lowlife foggers
have feelings too.
Alright. Light it up.
GRID: 30 seconds until overload.
Evacuation incomplete.
Utility tunnel locking down.
Sealed.
Depressurization imminent.
You know, you might even
find yourself a wife there
one of these nights.
JUDE: Another mouth to feed,
great plan.
How the hell am I going to
have time for a wife
when I'm stuck down here
witín hiệu your ass every day?
Ngay đây.
ETHAN: Light it up, baby.
Ah!
GRID: Power reroute complete.
System stabilized.
Các công nhân, hãy đứng thành một hàng.
A reminder that oxygen credits
are not transferable.
ChroniCorp... Hít thở dễ dàng.
Uh, I can't, uh,
do my shift tomorrow,
but it's not a problem.
Uh...
- I'll take it.
- I can make it up.
No. It's not my fault
you don't want to get paid.
- I'll take his shift.
- We're ahead, boss.
Được. Cậu vào. Anh ta ra.
Permanently.
Hả? Không,.. này.
- ETHAN: You good?
- JUDE: Yeah, man.
It's more money in the pocket.
GRID:
O2 is currently at 3.3%.
ETHAN: Come on. Let's go.
Where the hell is he?
MAN: Hey, man.
JUDE: Georgie, I need the money
tomorrow.
He owes me money for that.
Hey, Jerry.
How you doing?
There's no fire without oxygen.
Yeah.
You got any smart ideas?
- Get out of here.
- There's no fire without oxygen.
- Hey.
- Why don't you just leave it?
- No. You listen to me.
- There's no fire without oxygen.
- It's always something.
...for generations to come.
Hey. No, listen.
We have to sacrifice it all
for the generations to...
[COUGHS]
Oxygen is not a privilege.
You're not listening,
and I will make you listen.
- Okay. Alright.
- I need my job.
- Get off me.
- My kids got the sickness too.
- I will make you listen.
- What do you want me to do?
- We all need to...
- Listen to me.
You know that oxygen
is not a privilege.
REPORTER:
Another suicide protest today
marked the anniversary
of the death
of the last
living plant in captivity.
Since the believed extinction
of plant life,
deaths have continued
to spiral out of control
due to biophysical rejections
of the synthetic oxygen
that humanity
has come to rely on.
As the leading distributor
of synthetic O2,
ChroniCorp is still committed
to finding a solution
to this oxygen crisis that the
world has termed The Sickness.
However, citizens continue
to revolt amid fears
that this may be the end
for humankind.
ChroniCorp's quantum physicist
Dr. Richard Whyte
once radically posed that
in the unlikely event
that humanity
survives this crisis,
could we somehow find a solution
from our descendants
in the future?
Some suggest that his death
some 20 years ago
is linked to...
[SIGHS]
- Oh, my...
- Hi.
Hi.
Did I just hear your dad's name?
I got something for you.
Oh?
- Close your eyes.
- Okay.
- Are they closed?
- Yes.
- Alright. Keep them closed.
- Mm-hmm.
Keep them closed.
Okay. Okay.
Open.
What did you do this time?
See, um, the strap is loose
on the other one, and I...
I... I still have to seal it,
and, well,
this one is compatible
with the high-grade O2.
I don't need that.
Okay. It's fine.
I-I-I got a new shift.
Nhưng đây là thời trang.
Nó trông tuyệt đẹp.
Đương nhiên.
Thật luôn?
Ồ, sao vậy?
Anh không muốn trở nên
lung linh sao?
Em định làm gì vậy?
Đâu có
Don't... Don't start this again.
Remember what they said.
- You need to calm down.
- Okay.
You need... you... you...
you need to relax.
Thôi chết.
Em không sao chứ?
Xin lỗi anh.
Cứ việc để đó cho anh
Không sao đâu.
Làm ơn.
Nó ổn mà.
Chết tiệt.
Công dân số 34465?
We've been instructed
to bring you upstairs.
JUDE: We've got clearance
to be down here.
He doesn't like to be touched.
Anh ta đi nếu tôi đi.
Chỉ việc xem họ muốn nói gì thôi.
Đi nào.
Hoan nghênh công dân.
Welcome to the Applied Sciences
Division of ChroniCorp.
ChroniCorp is proud to be
the largest supplier
of breathable air
to the people of the world.
ChroniCorp... Breathe easy.
Hoan nghênh công dân.
Welcome to the Applied Sciences
Division of ChroniCorp.
ChroniCorp is proud to be
the largest supplier
of breathable air
to the people of the world.
REGINA: Even the fires
burn themselves out.
Họ cũng không thể hít thở được.
Tên tôi là Regina Jackson.
I'm the CTO of
Particle Research.
Còn cậu là... Ethan Whyte.
Ừm, đúng, là tôi.
Vợ cậu thế nào?
Our records show...
Tôi đang chăm sóc cho cô ấy.
We've all accepted
that things today
are even worse
than what scientists predicted.
The fact is
the O2 rejection epidemic
is going to wipe out the human
race within a handful of years.
I appreciate you bringing us
up here, but...
but what exactly
are you offering?
Sẽ ra sao nếu tôi nói rằng
cậu có thể cứu lấy chúng ta?
I-I'd hate to seem like
I don't appreciate
this show-and-tell,
but I think we should go.
REGINA: Your security
has been upgraded.
Cậu sẽ được thông báo tại phòng thí nghiệm.
Welcome to our Hail Mary.
Meet the Chronicle.
Billy Mitchell.
An absolute honor
to meet you, Ethan.
So you're the one.
Thật thú vị.
Ethan, do you know
what your father did here?
Được rồi.
3 phút, 10 giây.
Calibration is within tolerance.
REGINA: It's taken us 20 years.
If only your father
could see this.
My father's not here, is he?
Right. Of course. I'm sorry.
During our first trial,
we tested the Chronicle
with something that wouldn't
take as much power as matter...
radio waves to act
like a sort of tín hiệu
to see what was
on the other side.
The radio waves bounced back,
but they had been changed.
Có thứ gì đó được mã hóa bên trong.
Bounced back, what?
What do you mean, bounced back?
From where?
Not where, when.
Chúng tôi đã nhận được một tin nhấn từ tương lai.
Từ tương lai?
This is a fucking time machine?
Cách hiện tại 407 năm.
400 năm?
Bà đang nói với tôi rằng
loài người vẫn còn sống?
Tin nhắn này ngắn gọn, Ethan.
Grid, giải mã
tệp tin Chronicle số 170681.
Trên kia.
GỬI............................
GỬI ETHAN..............
GỬI ETHAN WHITE
REGINA: The people
who sent the message
must have found a cure
for the O2 sickness.
Nó là điều không thể.
There's no other way
they could still be alive
that far in the future.
We think they want to give
the cure to us
so that we could
save more people here.
Why ask for me?
We don't exactly know why,
but we may only get one shot
at sending someone.
One shot?
The Chronicle feeds off the
nuclear reactor under the city.
Just to fire a clock
a few phút through time
knocks large sections
of the city off the grid.
To fire the mass
of a human that far?
Let's just say I hope we
don't have to try this twice.
Why do I get the feeling
that there's a catch?
Ethan, we don't know yet
how to bring you back.
You want to shoot me
into oblivion with...
with no way to get home?
Cậu phải tìm ra
những người đã gửi tin nhắn này.
Họ có thể giúp cậu quay trở về.
You have got to find the cure.
You may be humanity's
only chance.
You may be your wife's
MAN: Beautiful, crisp,
clean air, all you can breathe,
chỉ 20$/h.
JUDE: Have you ever seen
anything like that shit before?
- Two more.
- It's all very impressive.
I'm not leaving Xanthe
as a favor to those ghouls.
Use it.
He's buying.
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
À. Được rồi...
Có vấn đề gì với em vậy?
Gì cơ?
Anh... anh có thực sự tin rằng
em sẽ đi cứu thế giới?
Very romantic.
You need to take this seriously.
Your old man believed them.
My old man was a fool
and a liar.
What if there's more
to his story, Ethan?
Story?
You want to hear more?
A father leaves a suicide note
for his 8-year-old son.
If he'd just been there instead
of chasing fucking rainbows,
my mother would
still be alive.
Very heroic,
and as if this wasn't enough
of a reminder of that,
you want me to do what?
Follow in his footsteps
to leave my sick wife to die?
I remember when I brought you
down in the tunnels
for the first time.
You were so scared
of just being left alone.
Còn nhớ những gì anh nói không?
"Without the darkness,
there's no light."
Stupid saying.
Má em.
Nghe này, cái đầu ngốc.
I've been through hell
and back in this life.
I've lost my family,
damn near lost my mind.
I've been working in
those fucking tunnels
for as long as I can remember,
and the only thing
I know that works
is when we fight for ourselves,
protect what's ours.
I can protect Xanthe.
I'm not just going
to abandon her.
And what are you going to do
when she gets worse?
This ain't about
saving the world, bro.
Em muốn chứng minh
rằng em không như ông ta?
Cứu cô ấy đi.
[DOOR OPENS]
He's been waiting for you
all day.
RICHARD: I made this for you,
Ethy,
because I have it
on good authority
that you are going to grow up
to be someone very important.
A science man?
A science man.
Now, this is going to hurt
a little,
but it will help you become
who you are meant to be.
Now, one day you'll understand.
You will want to trust what you
can see with your own eyes,
but it won't be enough, and you
will need to make a choice
about whether you believe
in something bigger.
Believe in what?
Believe in people.
[WHIRS]
[GASPS]
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
I'm sorry, Ethy.
You're done.
It won't come off.
SELENE: What's wrong with you?
ETHAN: Papa...
SELENE: Don't you dare
leave us again.
When?
I'm not leaving you to chase
some stupid fantasy.
You think a second chance
is a fantasy?
How could you say that?
Fucking scientists.
Do you think your tool kit
is important right now?
My tools need to be clean.
Look at me.
I have responsibilities here.
I need to meet my shifts.
We're... We're so close
to having enough for
the high-grade O2.
That could help you.
It could slow down the symptoms.
Don't do that.
What?
You can say that you're afraid,
but don't you dare use me
as an excuse.
You're better than that, Ethan.
What?
What are you talking about?
You're everything to me.
I-I can look after you.
I can help you.
I-I can make more money.
I can make you okay.
Who's to say that time
is anything
we should mess with anyway?
What if I can't change anything?
Who's to say that we can't?
Okay. What if I could?
What if I mess with something,
and it makes everything worse?
I can't believe what I'm hearing
right now.
No. I'm not going to risk
losing you.
XANTHE: You can't lose me.
Of course I can.
You've got to have faith, Eth,
that you can be bigger.
Faith isn't going
to protect you.
Now is not the time to have
your tail between your legs.
We're a team.
Why aren't you on my side?
Last year, I had
20 kids in my class.
This year, I have 12.
I saw three of them suffocate
right in front of me.
You're the only one
I care about.
I wouldn't be with you
if I thought that was true.
I'm afraid too, Ethan.
I know that you'll come back
to me.
Em tin vào anh.
Cha!
Khốn khiếp.
Cha...
Cha em không còn đây.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SCREAMS]
I don't care if I can only find
one dose of this cure.
Xanthe gets the first one,
or I'm not going.
You need me.
Được, Ethan.
Chúng ta có thỏa thuận.
ETHAN WHYTE
DỰ ÁN CHRONICAL SỐ 14
BILLY: These aren't just
space suits, Ethan.
These are my babies.
Fenrir is not quite ready,
but, Tyr, she'll get you there.
She'll protect you.
The Chronicle, at this time,
can't tether to itself
in the future.
There's something wrong
at the other end.
What the hell does that mean?
It means we're going to
have to throw you there.
Ném tôi ra đó?
BILLY: Without being tethered
at the other end,
there's a chance you could land
inside a mountain
or the ocean, so...
You've got to be kidding me.
We have to aim a little higher.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
REGINA: We'll land you as close
as we can
to the source
of the radio waves.
You just find the people.
Track them down and bring
the cure back home to us.
ETHAN: Sounds easy.
This may be humankind's
most critical journey.
I'm counting on you to find
a way back, Ethan.
Được rồi.
Một lần nữa, tập trung.
Đây là ai?
A-Archie.
Đúng rồi
Archie có thể làm gì?
ETHAN: Um, systems analysis,
navigation, communication.
Ừ. Đúng rồi.
Archie là người bạn duy nhất của cậu,
nên bảo quản cô ấy thật tốt.
The suit will feed your vitals
back to us from Archie,
so we're going
to know you're safe.
We'll be watching.
Hít thở sâu.
Nhìn chú này.
Đừng để mất.
Định thời lượng tử chuyển tiếp.
Chăm sóc cô ấy giùm em.
Cho tới khi em quay về thôi đấy.
Hẹn gặp lại, người anh em.
Mang lại tia sáng về đây.
Mồi lửa trong
Mồi lửa trong 20
Mồi lửa trong 19
Mồi lửa trong 18
Mồi lửa trong 17
Mồi lửa trong 16
Mồi lửa trong 15
Mồi lửa trong 14
Mồi lửa trong 13
Mồi lửa trong 12
Mồi lửa trong 11
Mồi lửa trong 10
Mồi lửa trong 9
Mồi lửa trong 8
Mồi lửa trong 7
Mồi lửa trong 6
Mồi lửa trong 5
Mồi lửa trong 4
Mồi lửa trong 3
Mồi lửa trong 2
Mồi lửa trong 1
Ethan.
Xin chào.
Nhanh nào.
Ethan Whyte. xin vào trong!
Ethan Whyte tới vị trí. Xin vào trong!
Archie?
Xin chào, Ethan.
Archie, ta đang ở đâu?
Để tôi tim kiếm vệ tinh.
Không tìm thấy vệ tinh.
Vị trí không xác định.
Đang tìm.
Không tìm thấy vệ tinh.
Archie, địa lí từ tính, đi.
Tôi đã tìm ra được một kiến trúc.
Cách đây không xa.
Theo tôi.
Chết tiệt.
ETHAN WHYTE
DỰ ÁN CHRONICAL SỐ 14
Tôi sẽ chết ở đây sao?
Mẹ kiếp mày.
Archie?
Tôi đây, Ethan.
Tại sao lại có hai tôi
ở đó cùng một lúc?
Tôi không nghĩ đây là bạn thứ hai, Ethan.
Tôi nghĩ đây là chính bạn.
Vậy là tôi đã chết và còn sống cùng lúc sao?
Ngay cả tôi cũng gặp khó khăn
với việc du hành thời gian, Ethan.
Cực kì hữu ích, cảm ơn.
Đây là nhiệm vụ của tôi.
Archie?
Vâng, Ethan?
Trạng thái.
Năng lượng còn 2%,
màn hình không hoạt động.
Phát lại đoạn ghi cuối cùng.
Tôi sẽ chết ở đây sao?
Có lẽ thế này sẽ tốt hơn.
Sẽ không ai bị ảnh hưởng thêm.
Em đã phải hy sinh điều gì?
Anh là gia đình em.
Anh làm vì em.
Đây là số phận của chúng ta.
A
Làm đi!
Bắn đi!
Làm ơn, đừng mà!
Mất nguồn.
Đang tắt, tạm biệt.
Đừng!
Archie!
ĐÃ TÌM THẤY TÍN HIỆU
Chẩn đoán.
Đã tìm thấy tín hiệu.
Là một đèn hiệu khẩn cấp.
Chúng ta nên liên lạc.
Theo tôi.
MÁY BỔ SUNG OXY
Xin chào?
Chà xát các que lại với nhau.
Ma sát tạo ra lửa.
Đơn giản, nhẹ nhàng.
Chà. Chà.
Lửa cần chút thời gian, Ethan.
Nhanh nào.
Cọ, cọ, cọ.
Kể cả tôi cũng gặp khó khăn với lửa.
Cố lên!
Hãy kiên nhẫn!
Đơn giản, nhẹ nhàng.
Trời!
Cọ, cọ, cọ!
Ngon!
Tốt lắm
Lúc này hãy thổi.
Phù, phù, phù, phù.
Lửa kìa!
Đơn giản, nhẹ nhàng.
Không nhận dạng được.
Ồ, cảm ơn.
A.
Đang quét.
Sự hình thành sao được đồng bộ hóa.
Thời điểm... 2474 SCN.
Những ngôi sao.
Những ngôi sao...
Chúng ta những ngôi sao như thế nào?
Điều đó thật ngớ ngẩn
Được rồi.
Thế này đi.
Con thấy đấy, Ethy,
Ta sẽ không để
chuyện gì xảy đến với con.
Khốn khiếp!
Đồ khỉ gió!
A!
Chờ đã, Ethan.
Ngươi không phải thật!
Ethan, em đang ảo giác.
Cái... Cái gì cơ?
Em tự đầu đọc chính mình...
bằng quả việt quất.
Jude?
Sẽ ổn thôi, nhóc. Miễn là làm theo
những gì anh nói.
Ngay sau đó, bọn anh biết
có gì đó không ổn.
Bên anh nghe thấy
mạch đập của em vọng lại.
Rồi độc tính trong máu tăng đột biến.
Chất độc.
Tim ngừng đập.
Biết không, anh
chứng kiến em chết đấy, Eth.
Em đâu có chết.
đúng không?
Anh không nghĩ vậy.
Nhưng Billy nói rằng chú ấy
chỉ có đủ năng lượng...
để kích hoạt Chronicle lần cuối.
Anh chộp lấy bộ đồ thứ 2.
Không thể bỏ em lại đây một mình.
Anh nói với chú rằng
anh có thể đưa em về.
Anh đến vì em.
Anh rơi xuống đất như tấn gạch.
Mọi thứ bị thiêu rụi...
cả bộ đồ của anh nữa.
Chỉ là anh mừng vì nhóc còn sống,
hạnh phúc khi thấy cái đầu ngốc của em,
hạnh phúc vì có thể thở
mà không cần cái mặt nạ chết tiệt đó.
Xanthe?
Cô ấy thực sự cần em.
Có vấn đề ở đây.
Cái quái gì đây?
Em đã nghĩ anh cứu em,
nhưng em vẫn chết.
ETHAN WHYTE
DỰ ÁN CHRONICAL SỐ 14
Không đúng.
Không. Cái này không đúng.
Ý anh là, đây không phải em.
Anh vừa nói là
em bị đầu đọc mà.
Đã từng.
Ý anh, bọn anh đã thay đổi điều đó.
đúng không nhỉ?
Có gì đó rất bất ổn.
Anh nghĩ gì?
Nghe này, ở đây còn gì nữa không?
Là... Là cái gì cơ?
Một cây súng à?
Em nghĩ ai đó để lại cái lỗ
đó trên đầu em rồi bỏ trốn.
Nghe này, cái chỗ xương chết tiệt
này không phải em.
Lại ăn quả mọng rồi à?
Xem nào, ai đó đã gửi cho em,
cái để họ sống sót
mất khoảng lâu để tái tạo nơi này,
Hẳn họ đã tìm ra phương pháp.
Nếu em không tìm họ lúc này,
Xanthe...
Rồi, tìm họ thôi.
Ử
Có lí do để chúng ta tới đây.
Giờ ta sẽ đi theo hướng đó.
Bão hòa đèn hiệu khẩn cấp đạt 98%.
Gần hơn rồi.
Sẵn sàng chưa?
Xem có ai ở nhà không.
Anh trông vào em.
Xin chào?
Cẩn thận.
Ethan!
Này, ở lại đi, Jude.
Chẳng thấy gì cả.
CHÀO ETHAN WHYTE
NHẤN ENTER ĐỂ KÍCH HOẠT
Kích hoạt gì cơ?
KHỞI TẠO MẪU DNA
A!
Chết tiệt!
Ra ngoài ngay!
ĐÃ PHÂN TÍCH MẪU DNA
ĐÃ CẤP QUYỀN TRUY CẬP: ETHAN WHYTE
Truy cập?
Không thể nào.
Chào bạn, Grid 1.
Là Hail Mary đấy.
Xin chào, hạ cấp xuống 1270.
Ethan Whyte, đã xác thực danh tính DNA.
Đã cấp quyền truy cập Chronicle.
Bắt đầu trình tự chuẩn bị cổng thông tin.
Bắt đầu đếm ngược.
Cổng sẽ kích hoạt trong bốn giờ.
Thời điểm: năm 2067 SCN.
Ethan.
Ethan, nếu những thứ này
vẫn còn hoạt động,
chúng ta có thể dùng nó để về nhà.
Mọi người đâu cả rồi?
Trông chẳng giống nhà của ai cả.
Điều này thật vô lí.
Sai hết cả rồi.
Anh chỉ đang nhìn thấy những gì trước mắt,
rồi thấy một cái thuyền cứu sinh.
Em tưởng anh đã cứu em
khỏi chất độc
Rằng nó đã thay đổi cả quá trình
Rõ ràng, chẳng có gì thay đổi cả.
Nghĩa là sao?
Nghĩa là có thứ gì đó
còn lớn hơn đang diễn ra.
Lúc mà thiết bị này quét máu của em,
Cái đèn, vừa nãy nó mới màu đỏ.
giờ nó thành màu xanh rồi.
Cái này, của bộ xương đấy,
cũng là màu xanh.
Rồi sao?
Nghĩa là em đã từng chết ở đây rồi.
Em chết hả?
Mỗi bước em đi, anh ta cũng thế
Em có đang lắng nghe
bản thân không đấy?
Làm thế nào nó xảy ra được?
Anh ta giống như tương lai của em.
Như kiểu em trở thành anh ta vậy
Đó là điều không thể!
Em cần phải hạ mình xuống.
Em đang mất trí đấy.
Grid?
Vâng, Ethan?
Thứ này có cho tôi quyền truy cập
vào dữ liệu sao lưu của Chronicle không?
Vâng, Ethan.
Giải mã nhật kí hệ thống.
Nhật kí Chronicle số 1...
Chúng ta đang ở khởi đầu của hành trình
có thể thay đổi mọi thứ.
Tôi là
Giáo sư Richard Whyte,
nhà vật lí đứng đầu dự án Chronicle.
Chúng tôi đã phát hiện ra
sự bất thường trong trường Higgs,
điều có thể sớm cho phép gửi sóng vô tuyến
và cả vật chất theo thời gian.
Dừng!
Em nghĩ gì khi nghĩ rằng có thể tìm ra
thứ em đang tìm kiếm?
Em phải làm.
Không, đừng làm thế.
Chúng tôi đã lấp một
trạm giám sát khí quyển.
Nó sẽ tiếp tục hoạt động,
và cho đến khi đạt đến
thời điểm ở tương lai
khi không khí có thể thở được,
nó sẽ gửi dữ liệu cho chúng tôi qua Chronicle.
Hy vọng của chúng tôi là Chronicle
sẽ giúp ta học được
từ con cháu ta cách họ
bổ sung oxy.
Đủ rồi.
Cái này hại nhiều hơn giúp.
Em đâu thể trốn khỏi ông ấy mãi được.
Làm ơn.
Nhật kí số 97.
Cố gắng lên nào mọi người.
Chuẩn bị đếm ngược.
Toàn bộ cuộc sống của chúng ta
dồn vào khoảnh khắc này.
Chúng tôi đang chuẩn bị cho
đối tượng Chronicle thứ nhất,
Gói sóng vô tuyến sẽ gửi tới
Chronicle ở tương lai.
Nếu thành công,
Chúng tôi sẽ nhận được tiếng vang
của dữ liệu về mức độ oxy.
Gửi tín hiệu trong
Gửi tín hiệu trong 3
Gửi tín hiệu trong 2
Gửi tín hiệu trong 1
Đã nhận tiếng vang.
Tín hiệu trở lại.
Thời gian... năm 2474 SCN.
Hoạt động rồi!
Dữ liệu đã được giải mã.
Dữ liệu đã được ghi đè thủ công tại đầu cuối.
Các từ tiếng Anh đã được giải mã
trong bộ phiên dịch.
Tiếng Anh? Gì cơ?
GỬI............................
GỬI ETHAN..............
GỬI ETHAN WHITE
Chúa ơi.
Nó nói cái gì vậy?
Tôi đâu có làm chuyện này.
Sao có thể xảy ra được?
Ông cần phải thực hiện thành công thứ này.
Nó đang hoạt động.
Có ai đang nhắc đến con trai tôi..
Thế quái nào họ biết được con trai ông?
Tôi không biết được.
Đừng nói với tôi như vậy.
Tất cả chúng ta là một gia đình.
Nó đang hoạt động.
Ai đó đã gửi cho ta tin nhắn này.
Bên đầu kia có ai đó.
Vậy thì ta chuyển sang giai đoạn kế tiếp
Bao lâu nữa chúng ta
có thể thử nghiệm việc gửi vật chất?
Không thể.
Nói.
Có một vấn đề với năng lượng ở năm 2474.
Cảnh báo
Lõi năng lượng hạt nhân ngừng hoạt động
Hệ thống Chronicle ngừng hoạt động
Archie, chẩn đoán.
Lõi hạt nhân,
nguồn điện lạnh tổng hợp gặp trục trặc.
Nghĩa là sao?
Cổng sẽ không liên kết tới năm 2067, Ethan.
Không đủ năng lượng.
Archie, tìm nơi phát sinh lỗi?
Đang tìm....
Phòng điều khiển lõi năng lượng,
Truy cập đường hầm dịch vụ số 7.
Grid?
Vâng, Jude Mathers?
Tại sao việc đếm ngược
không dừng lại được?
Jude Mathers,
trình tự thiết lập của Chronicle
đã thực hiện và không thể dừng lại được.
Hệ thống sẽ đạt đến
mức độ hạt không ổn định.
Không ổn định là sao?
Nếu nguồn cấp điện không được nối lại
trước khi đếm ngược trở về 0,
Các hạt tích điện trong Chronicle
sẽ tạo ra một vụ nổ hạt nhân.
Vụ nổ hạt nhân nghe không ổn chút nào.
Đừng chết lúc này, Eth.
Khoan đã.
Nếu họ đã nhận được tin nhắn này từ trước,
hẳn họ đã biết về lỗi năng lượng.
Grid, nếu ta sửa được
nguồn của Chronicle,
Cổng sẽ mở trong bao lâu
trước khi lõi hạt nhân cạn kiệt?
Một khi đếm ngược trở về 0,
Cổng sẽ kết nối đến năm 2067
trong khoảng 30 giây.
JUDE: Eth, mất một lúc ta
mới có thể xuống tới lõi được.
Chúng ta cần thực hiện ngay giờ.
Thưa chúa Jesus
Người có thấy những gì
con vừa thấy không?
Có ai đó gửi tín hiệu từ đây!
C-có nghĩa là
họ đã sửa nơi này.
Nghĩa là họ hẳn phải có phương pháp!
Họ có thể giúp em cứu lấy Xanthe.
Ừ thì, ai đó đã gửi tin nhắn,
họ đâu có ở đây.
Sao họ lại không nói cho ta biết
về lỗi năng lượng?
Sao họ lại cử anh đến?
Hả?
Anh đến để cứu em mà,
tiêm thuốc giải vào
cơ thể đã chết của em.
Nhưng sao lại không gửi một người lính...
hay là một bác sĩ?
Ừ thì, còn ai đó suýt nữa tự sát
để cứu lấy cái mông
vô ơn của em nữa đây?
Nghe này.
Em đã đúng.
Ta không thể cứu lấy mọi người,
nhưng anh có thể cứu lấy em.
Đi thôi.
Khoan
Em đang nhầm lẫn.
Em cần tìm ra điều này.
Chúng ta chỉ có một lần
để sửa thứ này thôi
Một lần thôi đấy, Ethan.
Anh không thể làm mà thiếu em được,
nên cùng kiểm soát đi.
Chúng ta cần kiểm soát,
em trai à.
Em cần... cần chút thời gian.
Vậy em không muốn gặp lại
Xanthe lần nữa sao?
Ai cho anh nói thế với cô ấy.
Anh đang không định để em
tự giết chính mình đâu đấy.
Bỏ em ra.
Làm ơn, tỉnh lại đi, nhóc.
Ý anh, anh chưa bao giờ để em thất vọng,
nên đừng để anh thất vọng lúc này.
Vụ nổ hạt nhân sẽ xảy ra
trong 3 giờ 50 phút nữa.
Được rồi.
Có ai đó đã gửi tin nhắn,
họ không có ở đây.
Bây giờ ta chỉ cần đi xuống
đường hầm dẫn vào.
Ta chỉ cần bật nguồn lên,
rồi sau đó sẽ có đủ
thời gian để tìm ra họ.
3 giờ, 50 phút,
tích tắc.
Thành phố lẽ ra phải ở ngay đây.
KHU VỰC CÂY OXY
Họ không bao giờ tìm ra
cách để tồn tại cả.
Trái Đất chỉ việc chờ
chúng ta chết mà thôi.
Eth, em đưa chúng ta tới đâu thế?
Đây không phải là cách đâu.
BÀ XANTHE WHYTE - LỊCH SỬ VỀ THỰC VẬT
Họ chỉ vừa mới chết
ngay trong lớp học,
chỉ vừa mới ngồi đây.
Mọi thứ giờ trở nên tệ hơn.
Họ thậm chí còn không loại bỏ người chết.
Nghĩa là ta đã thất bại rồi sao?
Eth.
Đừng, Eth.
Ethan.
Xanthe.
Không sao đâu em.
ANH SẼ TÌM RA CON ĐƯỜNG TRỞ VỀ
ƯỚC GÌ ANH QUAY TRỞ LẠI
Sao anh dám đi như vậy hả.
Anh đâu rồi, Richard?
Anh vừa làm gì con vậy?
Không. Hả? Không.
Em... không...
Không, em không hiểu.
Anh cần phải tự nói với con mình đi.
Ethy...
Ethy, nghe ta nói đây.
Ta cần con đi bộ với mẹ một chút.
Con muốn ở nhà.
Ta sẽ gặp con
Ta hứa.
Con hiểu không?
Con phải tin bố lúc này.
Được rồi con.
Trèo qua đó đi con.
Nhanh, trèo đi con, chỉ cần làm thôi.
Cứ đi đi con.
Mẹ!
Trèo đi
Cứ leo lên đi.
Mẹ!
Ethan
Chúng tôi không có tiền.
Làm ơn, nó chỉ là một đứa bé thôi.
Làm ơn. Đừng!
Không!
Mẹ ơi.
Đừng.
Mẹ ơi, đừng mà.
Mẹ ơi.
Mẹ sẽ mãi bên con.
Không!
Mẹ ơi!
Ba ơi.
Hít thở đi.
Gắng lên, thở đi.
Em cần phải đấu tranh
cho bản thân mình lúc này.
Ba em không còn đây nữa.
Thở đi.
- Không!
- Thở đi.
Thở đi.
Em đây rồi.
- Chúa ơi.
- Em vừa trở lại với cô ấy.
Em phải...
Anh biết.
Sao em lại có thể bỏ cô ấy một mình?
Được rồi, em đã làm những
gì em cho là đúng, Eth.
Có đúng không?
Em đã hứa với cô ấy sẽ trở lại mà.
Chúng ta kiểm soát số phận
của mình đúng không?
Chỉ cần có mấy cái niềm tin chết tiệt.
Chỉ cần có niềm tin.
E-Em không thể
để mất cô ấy thêm nữa.
Đây không phải lỗi của em.
Em bỏ mặc cô ấy chết.
Này.
Em không phải ông ta, Eth.
Nếu ta không thể
thay đổi mọi thứ thì sao?
Có lẽ đây không phải nơi của chúng ta.
Không thể nào.
H-Hẳn phải có cách nào đó...
Chỉ toàn bụi và... bụi và xương.
Không thể là lối đi duy nhất được.
Không thể.
- Ta...
- Đừng lòng vòng nữa.
Có lẽ thế này sẽ tốt hơn.
Sẽ không ai bị ảnh hưởng nữa.
Đi nào.
Anh vừa nói gì?
Hả?
Gì?
Archie...
Archie, phát lại đoạn ghi cuối.
Ai đấy?
Có lẽ thế này sẽ tốt hơn.
Sẽ không ai bị ảnh hưởng nữa.
Xung đột dữ liệu.
Bỏ qua đoạn đầu.
Em phải hy sinh những gì?
Anh làm chuyện này vì em.
Anh làm chỉ vì bản thân mình thôi.
Đây là số phận của chúng ta, Ethan.
Chẳng còn cách nào khác đâu.
Khoan đã
Anh nói gì cơ?
Đừng!
Làm ơn, đừng!
Bắn anh đi!
Anh thật sự xin lỗi
Đừng.
Mất nguồn, đang tắt.
Anh đang...
Anh đang làm gì vậy?
Thế quái nào lại có
giọng anh trong thứ đó?
Anh nói em.
Tại sao lại giấu anh chuyện này?
Tại sao lại giấu anh chuyện này hả?
Thế sao anh lại có súng hả?
Đó là sự bảo vệ.
Khỏi cái gì?
Anh vừa nói là.
Nơi này, nó... nó chỉ toàn bụi với xương.
Bảo vệ khỏi gì hả, em?
Anh có định bắt chết em không hả,
anh trai?
Gì cơ?
Em đang mất trí rồi đấy.
Trong cái thứ đó không bao giờ là anh cả.
Jude, đưa em khẩu súng đi.
Mình đang kiểm soát.
Làm ơn đấy.
Sao em lại lừa anh?
Làm ơn đi, Jude.
- Đưa em khẩu súng.
- Ở yên đó.
- Chỉ...
- Ở yên tại đó.
Chỉ việc đưa em khẩu súng thôi, Jude.
Xin anh đấy.
Anh biết bộ xương em
ở đó như thế nào rồi, phải chứ?
Cảnh báo...
Vụ nổ hạt nhân sẽ xảy ra trong hai giờ nữa.
Làm ơn.
Đi!
Anh muốn nói em anh định làm gì?
Saving you from yourself. Move.
[ELECTRICITY POPtín hiệu]
Looks like we found our problem.
GRID: Emergency reroute
required.
ETHAN: It's so fried.
We've got to reroute the power.
Archie, reroute stability.
ARCHIE: Reroute stability 30%,
Ethan.
Okay. Hit it.
Come on.
[POWERING UP]
[POWERING DOWN]
ARCHIE: Power reroute failure.
Damn it.
Give us a fucking chance.
[RUMBLING]
GRID: Evacuate service chamber.
Eth, look out! The door.
[GRUNTS]
GRID: Depressurization required.
Grid, override.
GRID: Unable to comply.
ETHAN: It won't work.
We need to manually pull
the backup breaker
while the room
is depressurized.
Am I going to die in here?
GRID: Purging O2.
You aren't.
JUDE: Ethan!
Ethan!
No!
YOUNG ETHAN: Stars?
[DISTORTED]
How are we like stars?
[AIR RUSHING]
GRID: Power restored.
Nuclear core active.
JUDE: Grid, system status.
GRID: Chronicle systems online.
Critical systems nominal.
37 phút to portal launch.
Thank fucking Christ.
[LAUGHS]
Where does this go?
[PANEL BEEPS]
No.
No. No.
- What?
- How didn't I-I see it?
See what?
ETHAN: The... The...
The... The future. It's...
It's already written.
We're just turning
the fucking pages.
JUDE: Give that to me.
No.
Ethan, stop playing games.
I-I am going to die.
What happens next, Jude?
I-I thought that
when we changed my death,
it meant that I could
change fate...
mine, Xanthe's, everyone's.
But the skeleton, it...
it's still there.
My skeleton is still here.
Why are we still talking about
a fucking skeleton?
ETHAN: My skeleton is still here
because
we can't change anything.
Everything was always
going to play out this way.
No matter what we do,
it's leading us to that moment.
You're confusing yourself,
Ethan.
No.
We're going to go home,
and you're going to shoot me
in the head,
and I'm going to rot
in that hallway for 400 years.
Am I not useful to you anymore,
brother?
You wouldn't lie to me.
Why would I? Why would I?
Because you know I'm never
going to see her again.
I'm protecting you.
By putting a fucking gun
to my head?
[CRYING]
- Archie...
- Put that fucking thing away.
- ARCHIE: Yes, Ethan?
- ...play last recording.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
ETHAN: Please, no. No.
No.
Find me!
- I wouldn't.
- ETHAN: No!
[GUNSHOT]
Fuck.
The second I got here, it was...
it was staring me in the face.
I-I just didn't want
to believe it was you.
- It's not me, Ethan.
- ETHAN: Why?
Why wait until we get back
to do it?
Why not just fucking do it now?
How could you do that to me?
It's not the plan.
What plan?
- We've got to get out of here.
- What fucking plan?
If we leave now,
we can change everything.
Get off. Fuck!
- What fucking plan?
- You've got to trust me.
I'm protecting you,
God damn it.
Fuck!
Fuck.
GRID: 30 phút
to portal launch.
I'm in control.
This place is alive, Ethan.
There's no reason
we can't live here.
And leave everyone to die?
JUDE: Ethan.
There's no masks.
You can't stop them.
I saved you, Ethan,
but we can't save everyone.
You've lost your fucking mind.
Stay away from me.
JUDE: Ethan!
My birthday.
I've made a terrible mistake.
We can't play God.
We don't belong
in God's playground.
Jude, what the fuck?
You're not going to find
what you're looking for.
Ethan, no!
Ethan!
There is no other way.
RICHARD: We don't belong
in God's playground.
We don't belong
JUDE: It won't change anything.
RICHARD: Maybe one day
I'll be there, and I can say...
say this to your face.
All of this was for you, Ethan.
If I could give you the life
I never had,
then you'd know
that I love you.
Wouldn't you?
It's the hardest thing,
to admit what you're afraid of.
I never had a father.
I don't know if you know that.
Why do I run away?
I should have been there
for you.
I didn't know how.
I'm sorry.
Fuck.
Grid, dial home.
[BEEtín hiệu]
SELENE: Richard, where are you?
What have you done to him?
Sweetheart, I don't have time
to explain.
I need you to take Ethan
and leave the house.
Meet me where we first met.
SELENE: No. What? No.
I don't understand.
You're going to have
to tell him yourself.
Ethy.
Ethy, I need you to go
for a little walk with your mom.
YOUNG ETHAN: Papa,
I want to stay here.
RICHARD: I will meet you.
I promise.
You have to trust me now.
GRID: Entry granted.
RICHARD: End call.
Jude.
JUDE: I can't let you do it.
REGINA: What are you thinking
now, Richard?
RICHARD: This isn't about
finding a cure anymore, is it?
You want to escape,
just leave the world behind.
There is no cure.
That message was sent
by someone.
There must be a cure.
We have a responsibility.
It's too late for that.
This world is done, Richard.
You want to save them all?
Most of them would
cut your throat
for one breath of fresh air.
They wouldn't know what to do
with another chance.
You're wrong.
Even if we could save them,
humans are a virus.
The Earth will heal but never
while we're suffocating it.
- This isn't the way.
- This is the only way.
The Earth needs time
without us, so we jump ahead.
Start again, or humanity
dies for nothing.
Who, your chosen few?
I know you've lost people,
but you can't...
This isn't about me, Richard.
You're right.
People are going to have to die.
It's not an easy decision,
but it's the right one.
It's not what we want.
It's what we need.
You need to have faith.
You're the scientist here.
You want to talk about faith?
I am not risking the survival
of humanity on your faith.
BILLY: Hey, Richard.
Just wanted to say
thank you so much
for giving me this chance.
I've run the numbers,
and I'm sure it will work.
I've got the design team working
on a rough outline as we speak.
An outline for what?
What?
Wait.
Did Richard not authorize this?
Is it going to work or not?
I think so.
Yes, I mean,
it will take some time,
but I think we can eventually
jerry rig the Chronicle
to fire a person one way,
kind of like a...
a slingshot or a...
or a catapult.
That's suicide.
You're going to kill someone.
With some kind of protective
suit, they might have a chance.
All we need is one person
to fix the power
on the Chronicle
in the future, right?
We fix the power,
she opens up the portal,
and we can go safely through.
REGINA: The tín hiệu came back.
There's oxygen there.
It proves the plan
has already worked.
Earth regrows only because
mankind doesn't make it.
RICHARD: No!
I don't believe
it's the only way.
I've locked the system
so only Ethan's DNA
can activate the Chronicle
at the other end.
Somebody sent for him,
and whether you believe or not,
you need him if you want
to open the portal.
Can you do it?
Can you get one person through?
I mean, I think it might
be possible,
but it's Richard's science,
so...
Can you make it work?
- Can you make it work?
- Yes!
[RICHARD'S BODY THUDS]
[CRYING]
Oh, fuck! Fuck!
[SHOUTS]
Stop!
Damn it, stop! Stop.
Ms. Jackson, I-I don't...
I don't...
Go down with a team.
Make sure the boy stays alive.
You will be his guardian.
Let nothing happen to him.
You understand?
He's the key to everything now.
I know.
GRID: 30 phút
to portal launch.
Fuck you.
You fucking liar!
All this time, you used me!
You used me.
They used us.
I was just a kid, man.
They're still coming, Ethan,
even if you try and stop them,
and the world you care
so much about,
they died for nothing.
That can't be true.
We can't change the past.
Even if we could,
what would happen to this place?
What would happen to us?
I don't know!
But we can't leave
millions of people to die!
They have already died!
It's already happened, man!
There is no cure!
Eth, you said it yourself.
Things can't be changed,
little brother.
I'm not your brother.
You sound like your father now.
You know, if he had listened
to Jackson, he'd still be here.
Only the strong survive, Ethan.
So you bought yourself a place
in the new world.
What did you have to sacrifice?
Me?
Xanthe?
I am your family.
I did this for you.
You did this for yourself.
There has to be another way.
I have to stop this thing.
- No, I can't let you.
- I have to stop this thing.
There is no other way.
[GRUNTS]
This is our fate.
- [ETHAN GRUNTS]
- There is no other way.
[GRUNTS]
- What did you say?
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, no!
No, no!
- Fight me.
- [CHOKING]
Ethan, Ethan, Ethan.
Fight me.
- Fight me.
- Please!
- No! No!
- Fight me!
No!
No, no!
Don't do it!
- Fight me! Fight me!
- Please, no, no, no!
Fight me!
No! Help me!
You got to fight
for yourself now.
Fight me!
Help.
[SCREAMS]
Please.
You got to fight me.
I believe in you.
It is me.
I can change.
I'm so sorry.
[GUNSHOT]
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
[CRYING]
Ohh, geez.
[DEVICE BEEtín hiệu]
[COMPUTER BEEtín hiệu]
Distinguished friends,
you have stood with me
while you watched your world
fall down around you.
This is our time.
Each one of you
has played a part
in bringing us to this point.
History will not forget you.
This day will be marked
as the day that we proved
that we will not go quietly
into the night,
the day the human race
took control of its fate.
I have it on good authority
that you are going to grow up
to be someone very important.
This is going to hurt,
but it will help you become
who you are meant to be.
One day you'll understand it.
You will want to trust what you
can see with your own eyes,
but it won't be enough,
and you'll need to make a choice
about whether you believe
in something bigger.
- Archie?
- ARCHIE: Yes, Ethan?
Someone is here.
ARCHIE: Who is here, Ethan?
I'm here.
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
I believe.
YOUNG ETHAN: Believe in...
believe in what?
Believe in people.
- No!
- Fight me!
RICHARD: I'm sorry.
GRID: Incoming particle stream.
Ethan.
He's a liability.
Shoot him.
Leave him here.
Once we're gone,
it won't matter.
Remember the drill.
We have one shot.
Once the portal opens, we have
30 seconds to clear through.
GRID: 10, 9, 8, 7, 6,
5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0.
Tether interrupted.
Shutting down.
No.
No. No.
No!
[RATTLING]
ChroniCorp's headquarters
were raided just moments ago
after this news station
received an anonymous broadcast.
Officials seized hundreds
of believed-extinct plants.
If what we are hearing is true,
this may be the second chance
the world so desperately needs
for ecological regeneration.
Religious groups are already
calling it the deus ex machina,
or God out of the machine.
GRID: Entry request.
Entry request.
Security override.
[DOOR OPENS]
Xanthe Whyte?
[GASPS]
[CRYING]
YOUNG ETHAN: Stars?
How are we like stars?
Silly.
Okay. Here.
Here, try this.
What's between us?
Your hands.
No.
Here.
Imagine for a moment that we are
all physically connected
by the very fabric
of the universe.
An invisible field
that bonds us together,
everything in the universe.
It's you, me, the stars.
We are all connected
through time.
So you see, Ethy,
even when I'm not with you,
we are always together.
[PEACEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[PANTING]
[CHUCKLES]
[TRIUMPHANT MUSIC PLAYING]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
[WOMAN VOCALIZING]
[VOCALIZING CONTINUES]