Sub by oce
Lyric by Kairiki Bear
BLACK SUMMONER
There’s no understanding anymore
Just nonsense and frustration
I’m not interested in life
Tear up those sparkly dreams
My brain is empty, vacant, disgusting, and rotten
I don’t know, I don’t know, I’m just so tired
We’re cursed, cold, dark, and crazy
I don’t know how to prove I exist
Ambiguity? Little by little, my brain is DEAD
Happiness? Little by little, loneliness my therapist
Love? Little by little, frozen, vanished, END?
If I could smile by your side
I’d never be sad, no way, no way
I’d sweep aside a thousand wrongs
Walking to the future until the dawn comes
Reincarnation, memories of a previous life forgotten
A story of wiping out all regrets
Struggling and exposed, I’ll push forward